<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Whoami on ShaanksFR Blog</title><link>https://shaanksm.github.io/tags/whoami/</link><description>Recent content in Whoami on ShaanksFR Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shaanksm.github.io/tags/whoami/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://shaanksm.github.io/p/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shaanksm.github.io/p/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://shaanksm.github.io/p/hello-world/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hello World" />&lt;h1 id="en">EN&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Welcome to the enthralling realm of cybersecurity, where every line of code narrates a tale of challenges and discoveries. Ever since stepping into the halls of EPITA, an engineering school in Paris, my passion for cybersecurity has burgeoned like a flame hungry for knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Through this blog, I invite you to accompany me on my journey, from the status of a padawan to that of a Jedi in the expansive world of information security. Picture me as an apprentice mariner who, through writings, event participations, and shared reflections, aspires to become a fearless chief captain navigating the digital ocean.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While my heart lies in the web, where each vulnerability beckons exploration and fortification, I refuse to confine myself to a single playground. I actively strive to acquire cross-disciplinary skills, all the while keeping an eye on future challenges like reverse engineering and pwn, though they may not be immediate priorities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join me in this adventure where lines of code transform into virtual swords, and each step marks progress towards mastering the art of cybersecurity. May this blog serve as a testament to my learnings, successes, and failures, offering a glimpse into the ever-evolving world of the modern-day pirate, from apprentice mariner to chief captain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="fr">FR&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Bienvenue dans l&amp;rsquo;univers captivant de la cybersécurité, où chaque ligne de code raconte une histoire de défis et de découvertes. Depuis mes premiers pas à l&amp;rsquo;EPITA, école d&amp;rsquo;ingénieurs à Paris, mon amour pour la cybersécurité a grandi comme une flamme avide de connaissance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>À travers ce blog, je partage avec vous mon périple, du statut de padawan à celui de Jedi dans le vaste monde de la sécurité informatique. Imaginez-moi comme un apprenti marin qui, au fil des écrits, des participations à des événements et des réflexions partagées, aspire à devenir un chef capitaine intrépide dans l&amp;rsquo;océan numérique.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mon domaine de prédilection réside dans le web, où chaque vulnérabilité est une invitation à explorer et à renforcer la sécurité. Je m&amp;rsquo;efforce d&amp;rsquo;acquérir des compétences transversales, tout en gardant un œil sur des défis futurs tels que la crypto par exemple, même si ces derniers ne sont pas ma priorité immédiate.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rejoignez-moi dans cette aventure où les lignes de code deviennent des épées virtuelles et où chaque étape marque un pas de plus vers la maîtrise de l&amp;rsquo;art de la cybersécurité. Que ce blog soit le témoignage de mes apprentissages, de mes succès et de mes échecs, tout en offrant une fenêtre sur le monde en constante évolution du pirate moderne, de l&amp;rsquo;apprenti marin au chef capitaine.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>